我是奧利弗•奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年裡  我被困在地獄一般的小島上
After five years on a hellish island,
我回來只有一個目標
I have come home with only one goal--
拯救我的城市
to save my city.
但要達到目標  我不能像過去一樣成為兇手
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
為了紀念我的朋友  我只能偽裝成另一個人
To honor my friend's memory, I must be someone else.
成為另一個存在
I must be something else.
《綠箭俠》前情回顧
Previously on "Arrow"...
我們一直追蹤的一個人
There's a new player we've been tracking.
我們一直叫他喪鐘
We've been calling him...Deathstroke.
我有個提議給你們
I have a proposal for you men.
羅伊被注射了血清
Roy was injected with the serum.
還活著  不過我們得看著他
He's alive. But we are going to have to keep an eye on him.
遠離西婭
Stay away from Thea.
不  她在你身邊的時候非常不安全
No. She's not safe when she's around you.
你愛她  所以你要按我說的做
You love her, and that's why you're going to do what I'm asking.
你怎能不告訴我  馬爾科姆•梅林是我父親
How could you not tell me Malcolm Merlyn was my father?!
我那麼信任你
I believed in you.
就在半小時前
As of 30 minutes ago,
你的公司歸我了
your company belongs to me.
斯萊德  你為他工作
Slade. You're working for him.
我知道奧利弗•奎恩就是綠箭俠
I know Oliver Queen is the Arrow.
我覺得這個頭套眼睛開孔位置不太對
I don't think my eye holes line up properly.
其他人有這個問題嗎
Is anyone else having this problem?
-別緊張  -我就是很緊張
- Don't be nervous. - I'm a lot nervous.
即使對我們而言  這也算是大動作
This is a big move, even for us.
我們曾經利用大動作取得制勝先機
And we've cornered the market on big moves.
斯萊德讓我們別無選擇
Slade didn't give us any choice.
按照計劃而言  這可不是個好主意
Yeah, as far as plans go, this is not a good one.
費利西蒂  這是你的計劃
Felicity. This was your plan.
我覺得你其實沒批準
I didn't think you'd actually say yes.
我們到了
We're here.
羅伯特•奎恩
應用科學中心
那個人曾經為我工作過
Hey! That man used to work for me.
現在他為我們的敵人工作
And now he works for our enemy.
安保攝像頭已經搞定
Security cameras are down.
你們還記得萬能鑰匙嗎
You all remember the skeleton key?
威廉•塔克曼的禮物  就是那個同步信號之王
Courtesy of William Tockman, AKA the Clock King.
可以打開任何鎖  包括這一個
It can open any lock. Including this one.
這是我們遇見巴里的地方
This is where we met Barry.
這些是隨插即用的
These are plug n' play.
把它們固定在我們說好的地方
Fasten them to what we talked about.
其他的就交給C4炸彈吧
Let the C4 do the rest.
好久沒有搞過爆炸了
Been a while since I've blown anything up.
速戰速決
Quick and clean.
我是個炸彈客  真不敢相信我成了炸彈客
I'm a bomber. I can't believe I'm a bomber.
不知道能不能當做特殊技能寫進簡歷裡
I wonder if I can list that on my resume under special skills.
不許動
Freeze!
我們得走了
We have to go.
熱成像顯示建築裡已經沒人了
Thermal shows everybody's out.
只是一棟建築  奧利弗
It's just a building, Oliver.
綠   箭   俠
第二季 第十九集
奎恩集團回應爆炸事件
懦夫
Cowards.
什麼人會毫無必要的破壞
Who else would needlessly destroy cutting edge,
尖端科學與醫療技術
scientific and medical technology
而且這些技術
whose sole purpose
是為了把星城變成一個更健康更安全的地方
is to make Starling City a healthier and safer place?
作為奎恩集團的總裁
As CEO of Queen Consolidated,
我要對做下這種惡行的恐怖分子說幾句
I have a message to the terrorist who committed this unspeakable act.
你們將被抓住  並接受懲罰
You will be caught, and punished.
我鄭重聲明  在發現
For the record, I hated her
她是個大壞蛋之前我就很討厭她
before we found out she was a super villain.
好吧  斯萊德的目的是
Ok. Slade's goal is to create an army
利用米拉庫魯建立一支人體武器部隊
of human weapons using the Mirakuru.
為達到這個目的  他需要工業離心機
To do that, he needs an industrial centrifuge.
讓伊莎貝爾•羅切夫從你的家族手中
Which having Isabel Rochev steal Queen Consolidated
奪走奎恩集團讓他可以大展拳腳
from your family gave him full access to.
但是既然應用科學中心被炸了
But since Applied Sciences went kaboom,
他就沒法利用我們的技術
he can't use our technology--
我們以前的技術  來做他的邪惡試驗了
well, formerly ours for his warped science experiments.
幾周以來斯萊德一直緊緊相逼
Slade has had us on our heels for weeks.
我們跟他正面對決只是時間問題
It's about time we took the fight to him.
我們所做的一切就是為了讓他直接面對我們
All this will do is set him back.
我們無法知道下一次攻擊會來自哪裡
We have no way of knowing where the next attack is coming from.
奧利弗•奎恩回到星城
治安維持者在星城港口槍戰
兜帽治安維持者再度來襲
西婭•奎恩被兜帽男所救
聽著  你必須放下這事  好嗎
Look, you need to drop this, OK?
我沒事  真的
I'm fine. Really.
你怎麼可能沒事
How is any of this fine?
你要把注意力放在自己身上
Look, you need to concentrate on you.
你準備去參加會議嗎
Now listen, are you going to your meetings?
是的  我要去那裡說說我父親是怎麼入獄的
Yes. It's where I talk about how my father's facing prison.
勞蕾爾
Laurel...
這些都會過去的  好嗎  拜託了
This will all blow over, OK? Please.
不  不會的  爸爸
No. It won't, Dad.
你被抓住是因為幫助支持那個治安維持者
You were caught aiding and abetting the Vigilante.
去年跟他一起合作害你丟了警長之職
Working with him last year cost you your detective shield.
現在可能會害你入獄18個月
Now, it can cost you 18 months in prison.
他們想知道他的名字
They want his name.
你知道綠箭俠是誰嗎
Do you know who the Arrow is?
我不知道
I don't.
我發誓
I swear.
那黑衣女子呢
Ok, well, what about the woman in black?
跟綠箭俠在一起的那個
The one the Arrow works with?
你知道她是誰嗎
Do you know who she is?
-不知道  -那你肯定知道些什麼吧
- No. - Well, you must have some idea.
寶貝  我沒法告訴你我不知道的事
Honey, I can't tell you what I don't know.
時間到
Time's up.
孩子們  照顧好彼此
You girls, you take care of each other.
你真心覺得他不知道綠箭俠是誰嗎
Do you really think he doesn't know who the Arrow is?
爸爸不會撒謊
It's not like dad to lie.
有時最親近的人  才是最具欺騙性的
Sometimes it's people closest to us who lie to us best.
西婭去哪了
Where is Thea?
她應該也要到場的
She should be here for this, too.
我覺得她不會來了
I doubt she's coming.
我對你們就實話實說了
Well, I can't lie to either of you...
情況很糟糕
it's bad.
一旦伊莎貝爾•羅切夫掌權  就玩完了
If Isabel Rochev is one thing, it's thorough.
為了這次收購  她已經籌劃了好幾個月
She's been laying the foundation for this takeover for months.
但是我們仍然持有公司大部分股票  對吧
But we still own a majority of stock in the company, correct?
沒錯  但是伊莎貝爾削弱了股票的價值
Yes, but Isabel has diluted that stock
現在來說  它們分文不值
to the point where it's worthless.
在名義上  你們真的破產了
On paper, you're virtually broke.
那麼好消息是什麼
And what's the good news?
我們可以保護你們的資產
We can protect your assets.
我們需要把所有的財產
We need to move everything
轉移到伊莎貝爾碰不到的地方
into a new trust that Isabel can't touch.
我需要當下所有受惠人的簽名
All I need is the beneficiaries from the current trust
來授權此次財產轉移
to approve the transfer.
也就是你們兩位  還有西婭
The two of you and Thea.
西婭也需要簽字
Thea needs to sign off.
沒錯  而且是馬上
Yes. And quickly.
謝謝你  奈德
Thank you, Ned.
現在  我不得不成為市長了
Well, now I have to become mayor.
因為我需要這份工資
It seems I'll need the income.
失去公司  不是你的錯
Losing the company wasn't your fault.
是我的錯
It was mine.
我敗給了伊莎貝爾•羅切夫
I let Isabel Rochev get the better of me.
不是  你總是能看到別人好的一面
No. You always see the good in people,
哪怕他們不值得你如此
even if they don't deserve it.
我比誰都清楚這一點
I know that better than most.
伊莎貝爾報仇心切
Isabel is a vindictive woman.
不管你信任她與否  她都要達到目的
She would have done this with or without your trust.
你怎麼知道
How do you know?
你幾個月前告訴過我  不能相信她
You told me months ago I couldn't trust her.
你父親  容易屈服於
Your father had a weakness
美麗  並且強勢的女人
for beautiful, strong women.
他們在一起過
They were together?
沒錯
Yes.
當年她還是商學院的學生
She was still in business school at the time.
美麗的實習生頗受總裁的青睞
The pretty intern that caught the CEO's eye.
你把這個拿給西婭
You take this to Thea,
無論如何說服她  幫助我們反擊
and you convince her somehow, to help us fight back.
-能幫我一把嗎  -好的
- Will you help me up? - Yeah.
-去我的箱子那  -好的
- Just to my trunk. - Ok.
瞧瞧看誰起來啦
Oh, look who's up.
正好趕上看好戲
Just in time for all the fun.
你要對他做什麼
What are you going to do to him?
聽聽他的尖叫聲
Make him scream.
就像他對我們所做的
Just like he made us.
俗話說  活下來就是最好的復仇
They say living well is best revenge?
我覺得折磨才是
I prefer torture.
你想第一個來嗎
You want first turn?
不要  拜託
No, please.
我能幫助你們
I can help you.
不  博士  我能幫助你
No, doctor. I can help you.
你說過的  研究需要什麼來著
What was it you said you needed for research?
一隻眼睛
An eye?
不要
No!
我給你弄一隻新鮮的
Let me get you a fresh one.
你們還是可以阻止斯萊德•威爾遜的
You can still stop Slade Wilson!
阿納托利  慢著
Anatoly. Wait.
你剛剛說什麼
What did you say?
我能幫助你們阻止他
I can help you stop him.
怎麼阻止  你的神藥已經把他變成了怪物
How? That miracle drug has turned him into monster.
我知道  我能讓他變回來
I know. I can turn him back.
艾沃  你在說什麼
Ivo, what are you saying?!
米拉庫魯  它有解藥
The Mirakuru. There's a cure.
西婭在這裡嗎
Hey, is Thea here?
我沒有見到她
No, I haven't seen her.
你爸爸還好嗎
How's your dad?
為了綠箭俠進監獄  他心甘情願
He's willing to go to jail for the Arrow.
我知道你說不擔心
I know you said you weren't worried,
但是狄格和我還是去了羅伊的公寓
but Dig and I went to Roy's apartment.
現在人去樓空
It's empty.
看上去像是幾天前就搬走了
Seems like he cleared out a few days ago.
他會去哪呢
Where the hell did he go?
羅伊的事暫時緩一緩
Roy will have to wait.
我們現在要考慮的是斯萊德
We need to deal with Slade,
弄清楚他下一步的行動
figure out what his next move is.
我瞭解斯萊德
I know Slade.
他不會停手的  除非...
He is not going to stop till...
歡迎回家
Welcome home
你好  莎拉
Hello, Sara.
狄格爾  退後
Diggle, stay back!
你是在浪費子彈
You're wasting your bullets.
小子  別忘了是誰教你打架的
Don't forget who taught you how to fight, kid.
不好意思  我在找我妹妹莎拉•蘭斯
Excuse me, I'm looking for my sister, Sara Lance.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我是勞蕾爾•蘭斯  我妹妹還好嗎
I'm Laurel Lance. Is my sister ok?
她沒事的  手腕部有細微骨裂
Oh, she'll be fine. Just a hairline fracture of her wrist.
已經處理過了
We set it.
淤青挺嚇人的  看上去以為傷得很重
She's got some nasty bruises, looks worse than it is.
謝謝
Thank you.
與她的舊患相比  這不算什麼
Nothing compared to her previous injuries.
什麼舊患
Previous...injuries?
是的  你妹妹全身上下
Yes, your sister has extensive scar tissue
都有大量的瘢痕組織
over her entire body.
我上一次見到帶有如此多傷痕的人
The last person I saw with that much damage
是一名在伊拉克受傷的退伍軍人
was a veteran injured in Iraq.
你妹妹服過役嗎
Has your sister served in the military?
沒有
No.
她沒服過役
No, she hasn't.
莎拉
Sara.
-你來了  -到底發生了什麼事
- Hey. - What happened to you?
我沒事
Oh, I'm fine.
奧利和我騎摩托車時摔了一下而已
Ollie and I just had a little motorcycle mishap.
沒事的
It was nothing.
我已經辦好出院手續了
I already got my discharge papers.
但是你的背...
But your back...
那些傷痕  是怎麼來的
Those scars, where did you get them?
你沒事吧
You OK?
會沒事的  你呢
I will be. You?
我也沒事  勞蕾爾
Yeah. Yeah. Hi.
你來了  告訴我到底怎麼回事
Hi. So tell me what happened.
摩托車禍  笨死了
Motorcycle accident. It was stupid.
我們正要左拐時  一輛車闖了紅燈
We were making a left turn, this car ran a red light.
你們錄口供了嗎
Did you file a police report?
沒那個必要  我們倆都沒事
We didn't see the point. We're both fine.
這才是最重要的  不是嗎
That's-- that's what counts, right?
是
Right.
我真的該走了
I should really go.
一小時後我還要上庭
I have a deposition in an hour.
好的
OK.
謝謝你來看我
Thanks for checking up on me.
當然
Always.
我知道奧利弗•奎恩就是綠箭俠
I know Oliver Queen is the Arrow.
威登酒吧
你好
Hey.
你昨天沒去開會
We missed you yesterday.
跟奈德•福斯特的會
The meeting with Ned Foster.
西婭  我知道你在生我和媽的氣
Thea, I know that you're mad at mom and me,
但我們也許有辦法解決這次金融危機
but we may have found a way out of this financial mess
我們不會失去一切的
where we aren't going to lose everything.
媽媽和我都簽字了  我們...
Mom and I both signed, we just...
我們需要你的簽名
We need your signature,
希望能阻止伊莎貝爾毀了我們
and hopefully we can stop Isabel from ruining us.
你是說在你讓她毀了我們之後
After you let her ruin us, you mean?
是的
Yeah.
這裡說到西婭•奎恩
It says Thea Queen here.
那是誰
Who's she?
就是你  閃電妞
That's you, Speedy.
不是我
No, it's not.
羅伯特•奎恩不是我父親
Robert Queen wasn't my father.
馬爾科姆•梅林才是
Malcolm Merlyn was.
西婭•梅林
Thea Merlyn.
這個名字挺好聽的
Kind of has a nice ring to it.
梅林只是你的生父  是老爸養大你的
Merlyn was your biological father, but Dad raised you.
那是因為他不知道我不是他親生的
Only because he didn't know I wasn't his.
他很愛你的
He...He loved you.
我也是  我仍然還是你哥哥
So do I, and I am still your brother.
你不是  你是我同母異父的哥哥
No, you're not. You're my half brother.
知道我另一個同母異父的哥哥是誰嗎
And you know who else was my half brother?
是湯米
Tommy.
我曾經想要吻的那個湯米
Tommy, who I tried to kiss.
我曾經想要吻我同母異父的哥哥
I tried to kiss my half brother--
之後我親生父親竟然把他殺了
before my real father killed him!
我的人生就是這麼複雜
That's how screwed up I am!
知道嗎  最難過的是
And you know the sad part,
之前我的生活竟然要開始漸入佳境了
I was actually starting to be in a good place.
我有間夜店  有羅伊
I had the club, I had Roy,
有個對我說實話的哥哥
I had a brother who wasn't lying to me.
在我混亂的生活中第一次
And for the first time in my crazy life,
所有的一切還算過得去
everything didn't seem so completely and totally messed up.
我還以為我的人生會變好
I thought I was going to be OK.
我實在太蠢了
I'm so stupid.
你一點也不蠢
You're not stupid.
不  我是...
No, what I am...
兩個殺人成性的人的女兒
is the daughter of two mass murderers.
不止一個  是兩個
Not one, but two.
面對現實吧  奧利
So let's face it, Ollie.
我的人生是不會變好的
I was never going to be OK.
我的基因註定如此
It's not in my genes.
西婭
Thea...
奧利弗
Oliver.
我們現在要討論安全措施的問題
We need to discuss that security matter now.
情況如何
What do we have?
-斯萊德拿走的東西  -拿走的東西
- What Slade took. - Took?
他不是來殺我們的
He wasn't here to kill us.
他來是因為我們手上有他想要的東西
He was here because we had something that he wanted.
那把萬能鑰匙
The Skeleto Key.
我做了全面檢查  只有這把鑰匙不見了
I did a full sweep. It's the only thing that's missing.
現在他需要一種新方式來大規模生產血清
He needs a new way to mass produce the serum now that
因為我們炸毀了應用科學中心
we've dusted Applied Sciences.
擁有萬能鑰匙
With the Skeleton Key,
他能進入任何地方  拿到任何想要的東西
he can get into anywhere and take anything he wants.
我們知道他想要什麼
We know what he wants.
只需要先他一步找到
We just need to find it first.
星城最先進的技術
Where is the most cutting edge technology housed
在哪裡
in Starling City?
星級實驗室  星城
星級實驗室  倉庫數據庫
這是每個曾在星級實驗室
The combined inventory of every scientist
工作過的科學家的數據
who ever worked at S.T.A.R. Labs.
所有的都在這裡
All housed right in here.
因為我將這棟大樓命名為"屌炸天"
I hereby christen this building "Da bomb."
現在沒人這麼說了
Nobody says that anymore.
我就這麼說
I say it.
哥就是這麼酷
I define my own cool.
我還是難以相信威爾斯博士竟要關掉這個地方
I still can't believe Dr. Wells is shutting this place down.
尖端科研實驗室在我們打開粒子加速器時
S.T.A.R. Labs blew a hole in Central City
在中心城市內引起了大爆炸
when we turned the particle accelerator on.
星城要終止
It's not surprising that
對這個設施的租賃也在情理之中
Starling City cancelled the lease on this facility.
"讓我們來保管社區內無人管理的樣機吧"
We're not exactly the poster children for
我們這麼說了  但卻沒有做到
"Let us store our unregulated prototypes in your neighborhood."
那是個意外  凱特琳
It was an accident, Caitlin.
跟受害者家屬
Yeah, well, try telling
也這麼說試試看吧
that to the families of the people who died.
或許你應該先想想怎麼給自己一個交代
Maybe you can figure out how to tell that to yourself.
西斯科  把庫存盤點完  我們就能回家了
Look, Cisco, let's get this inventory done so we can go home.
我以為這裡沒別人了
I thought we were the only ones here...
或許是其中一個警衛
Maybe it's one of the security guards.
你好啊
Oh. Hey, man.
我們馬上就能結束了
We should be wrapped up any minute now.
你有沒有一種不祥的預感
Are you getting a bad vibe off this guy?
你讓我追你的時間越長
The longer you make me chase you,
我折磨你的時間就越長
the slower I will kill you.
幫幫我
Help me.
這個設備本屬於亞瑟•萊特
This equipment belonged to Arthur Light.
威爾斯兩年前把他炒了
Wells fired him two years ago.
-為什麼  -因為他是個瘋子
- Why? - Because he was a psycho.
你可千萬要搞定這東西啊
Please tell me you can make this work.
禁區  只有特準人員可進
我收回我剛說的話
I take back what I said--
我會速戰速決的
I'll make this quick.
不
No!
我們來晚了
We're too late.
-費利西蒂  -西斯科  凱特琳
- Felicity! - Cisco, Caitlin!
你們還好嗎  他沒傷害你們吧  他沒有吧
Are you guys ok? He didn't hurt you, did he?
你說了兩次"他"
You said "he" twice.
你知道襲擊我們的人是誰嗎
Do you know who attacked us?
那個戴著面具手拿長劍的瘋子
That lunatic with the mask and the sword?
不  我不知道
Uh, no. I--no, I don't know.
我說了兩遍"他"  因為我聽到廣播裡說
I--I said "he" twice, because on the radio,
襲擊你們的那個人有男性特徵
I heard that the person who attacked you had man parts,
所以我認為他是個男的
which would make him a...he.
我叫約翰•狄格爾  奎恩聯合企業的保安
I'm John Diggle, I work security for Queen Consolidated.
你知道面具男拿走什麼了嗎
Do you have any idea what the masked man may have taken?
比如一臺工業離心機之類的
an industrial centrifuge, by any chance?
無可奉告  這是個秘密
No. It's a secret.
什麼樣的秘密
What kind of secret?
不能說的秘密
The kind I have to keep.
西斯科也得保守這個秘密嗎
Well, does Cisco have to keep it, too?
-沒錯  -好吧
- Yes. He does. - Ok.
我們很高興看到你們倆都沒事
We're just so happy that you guys are ok.
巴里怎麼樣了
How's Barry doing?
老樣子
He's the same.
巴里的情況惡化了
Barry's condition deteriorated.
他們把他移到了尖端科技研究實驗室內照顧他
They moved him to S.T.A.R. Labs. They've been looking after him.
我就是因此而認識西斯科和凱特琳的
That's how I met Cisco and Caitlin.
是的
Right.
我一有空就會再去看他的
Well, I'll come visit again, as soon as I can.
那很好
That would be cool.
別擔心  很多人都來看巴里
Don't worry, Barry gets lots of visitors.
艾麗絲經常去那兒
Iris is there a lot.
艾麗絲嗎
Iris?
她是
She's, um,
他的
his...
某人
Something.
原來如此
Oh.
那好吧
Sure. Good.
真了不起
That's just swell.
巴里還在昏迷中就已經有進展了
Barry's in a coma and he's already moved on.
我侵入了哈里森•威爾斯的個人檔案
I hacked into Harrison Wells' personal files.
他是尖端科技研究實驗室的主管
He's the director S.T.A.R. Labs,
所以這差不多讓我可以查看任何資料
which basically makes me unstoppable.
看看我發現了什麼
And look what I found.
這是他們其中一個生物技術項目的原型
It's a prototype for one of their new bio-tech projects.
還沒有申請到專利
The patent is still pending,
或許這就是為什麼他們不想告訴我們
which is probably why they didn't
那到底是什麼東西
want to tell us what it was.
所以這到底是什麼
So what is it?
這是個生物傳輸導管
It's a biotransfuser.
它可以同時把血液從一個病人體內
It can deliver blood from one single patient
輸入到多個病人體內
into multiple patients, at once.
為什麼斯萊德需要輸血
Why would Slade need a blood transfusion?
他不需要
He doesn't.
但他為了創建自己的私人軍隊
The prisoners that he freed from Iron Heights last week
上周從鐵山監獄放走的那些囚犯需要
to create his own personal army do.
稍作調整  斯萊德就可以將它改造
With a few tweaks, Slade can retro-fit it for the Mirakuru,
用於米拉庫魯  而且他完全不用顧忌
bypassing what we know to be a less than desirable
失敗之後死亡率很高的問題
ratio of success to, you know, death.
這一切都將會在機器內進行
Instead of it metabolizing in the person,
而不是利用人體內新陳代謝
it happens in the machine.
這得需要大量的血液才行啊
That's going to require a whole lot of blood.
即使耐力非凡的斯萊德
Even a man with Slade's stamina
也承受不住那種血液流乾的痛苦
can't handle that kind of drain.
-很好  -你什麼意思
- Good. - What do you mean?
我們就讓他使用
We let him use it.
他會變得虛弱  不堪一擊
He'll be weak, vulnerable,
那時候就是我殺死他的好時機
and that will be my opportunity to kill him.
我們怎麼才能找到這個東西
How do we find this thing?
要啟動這樣的機器
A machine like this pulls an exorbitant
需要大量的電力支援
amount of power from the grid.
當它啟動時  我就會知道時間和地點
When it turns on, I'll know when and where.
現在  我們只能靜心等待
Right now, we just wait.
我受夠無盡等待了
I'm tired of waiting.
別聽他的  他在撒謊
Don't listen to him, he's lying!
解藥真的存在  我保證
The cure is real, I promise!
不  他只是想要活命才會這麼說的
No, he's just trying to save his neck.
安東尼  看著我
Anthony, look at me.
告訴我們解藥的事
Tell us about the cure.
我想幫助你  莎拉
I want to help you, Sara.
但首先  你要保證你也會幫我
But first, you have to promise you'll help me, too.
她救不了你的命
She can't save your life.
沒有人可以的
No one can, not anymore.
我只求一個痛快
All I ask is for is a quick death.
你不配那麼快解脫
You don't deserve a quick death.
我明白
I know.
但我依然請求你們
And I'm still asking.
這是你的決定
It's your call.
謝謝
Thank you.
快從實說來  艾沃
Start talking, Ivo!
我從來沒有成功地
I was never able to replicate the Mirakuru serum
從我發現的二戰時期日本的研究中
from the original Japanese World War II
復制出米拉庫魯血清
research I discovered.
經過一年的
After conducting experiments
人體試驗之後
on the prisoners that I acquired this past year,
我成功合成了一種溶液
I was able to synthesize a solution
能夠抵消和逆轉
that counteracts, reverses
米拉庫魯所產生的生理效應
the physiological effects that exposure to Mirakuru produces.
從擁有超人的能力
From more than human...
轉變回普通人類
back to human.
解藥現在在哪裡
Where is this cure now?
你會信守諾言結束我的生命嗎
You'll keep your word about ending my life?
對  快告訴我們
Yes. Tell us.
在貨船上
On the freighter.
在我房間的保險櫃裡
In the safe in my quarters.
我想
Now I believe...
我的這部分已經做完了
this concludes my end of our deal.
不管你要說什麼  反正一分鐘內
Whatever you came here to say, it takes security
保安就會上來
about 60 seconds to reach this floor,
所以我就陪你聊一會
so I would start talking.
斯萊德在哪裡
Where's Slade?
我只是給你機會做正確的事
I just wanted to give you the chance to do the right thing.
我不到30歲
I'm under 30,
擔任著財富500強企業的總裁
and I'm the CEO of a Fortune 500 company.
我想這足以說明我做了正確的事
I'd say I've already done the right thing.
你知道斯萊德•威爾遜是什麼樣的人嗎
And do you even know who Slade Wilson is?
或者他做這些是為了什麼
Or why he's doing this?
我不在乎
I don't care.
-這些都是我應得的  -你應得的
- I got what I earned. - What you earned?
你以為上了我爸爸的床
You think that sleeping with my father
他的公司就應該屬於你了嗎
entitles you to my family's company?
你根本不知道是怎麼回事
You have no idea what you're talking about.
他玩過不少女人
Wow, he fooled around with a lot of girls.
其他人可沒有來惡意收購的
I don't see any of them ordering hostile takeovers.
玩女人
Fooled around?
你媽是這麼跟你說的嗎
Is that what your mother told you?
她當然會把我說成一個無關緊要的小三
Of course she would write me off as a meaningless affair.
斯萊德•威爾遜讓我吃了很大的苦
Slade Wilson put me through hell.
他的魔鬼訓練差點害死了我
His training nearly killed me.
如果我只是個被拋棄的情人
Would I put myself through
我何必要去承受這些
all that just because I was a jilted lover?
說實話  我不知道你算什麼
Honestly, I don't know what you are!
我是你父親的摯愛
I was your father's soul mate.
他當時已經準備離開你母親
He was going to leave your mother,
離開公司  丟下你
leave the company, leave you.
-我們行李都整理好了  -是嗎
- Our bags were packed. - Really?
可你妹妹偏偏要摔壞胳膊
Your sister had to go and break her arm
做出些蠢事來
doing something ridiculous, no doubt.
她從馬背上摔下來了
She fell off her horse.
他接到電話的時候我們已經到機場了
We were at the airport when he got the call.
我求他不要回去
I begged him not to go.
我提醒他西婭甚至不是他親生的
I reminded him that Thea wasn't even his.
你是說我爸爸早就知道
Are you saying that my father knew?
他當然知道了
Of course he knew.
他是傻  但不是白癡
He was a fool, not an idiot.
就像傻瓜一樣  他還是很疼愛她
And like a fool, he loved her anyway.
他答應我第二天就離開
He promised me that we would leave the next day.
可恰恰相反  我的實習被終止了
But instead, my internship was terminated
他也再沒跟我說過一句話
and he never spoke to me again.
你就是為了這個吧
Oh, so that's what this is really about.
他為了我們拋棄了你
He chose us over you.
請把奎恩先生請出大樓
Please escort Mr. Queen off the premises.
別碰我
Don't touch me.
不要讓他再進這座大樓了
He's no longer welcome in this building.
這是我的地方
My building.
喂
Hello?
西婭  我是奧利
Thea, it's Ollie.
我想和你見面談  就五分鐘
Listen, I just need five minutes face to face.
你想幹什麼
What do you want?
有件事情需要告訴你
There's something you need to hear.
就五分鐘  酒吧關門後來吧
Five minutes. Come by the club after we close.
剛跟費利西蒂通過話
Just spoke with Felicity.
有人要找綠箭俠
Someone reached out to the Arrow.
見面談談
Wants a meeting.
是誰
Who?
勞蕾爾
Laurel.
待地舒服嗎  蘭斯警官
You comfortable in there, Officer Lance?
如果你冷的話我可以給你再找條毯子
I can see if there's an extra blanket if you're cold.
我很好  既然我現在關在這裡了
I'm good. But hey, now that I'm on this side of the bars,
你叫我昆汀就行了
I think it's just Quentin.
我相信這只是個誤會
I'm sure it's just a misunderstanding.
你很快就能出去了
You'll be out of here soon.
謝謝你的樂觀
Yeah, I appreciate your optimism.
你在幹什麼
Hey, what are you doing?
夥計
Hey, buddy.
警官  快來人啊  快來人啊
Officer! We need help! We need help!
你要幹什麼  夥計
Whoa, whoa, what are you doing, man?
記得我嗎
Remember me?
你該記得的  因為我記得你  警官
You should, 'cause I remember you, Officer.
不  你不能這麼做
No, you can't do this.
沒事的  別緊張
All right, take it easy.
就是因為你和那個穿帽衫的怪胎
'Cause you and that hooded freak show
我才進了這鬼地方
are the reason I'm in this place.
我覺得我應該過來招呼你一下
I thought I should be the one to welcome you.
這還沒完
This isn't over!
這沒完
This is not over!
我聽說你父親被捕了
I heard about your father being arrested.
如果我可以的話我會幫他的
If I could help him, I would.
我不是為了這件事叫你來的
That's not what this is about.
很有趣不是嗎
It's funny, isn't?
一年以前他以為你是個謀殺犯
A year ago, he thought you were a murderer.
而我  我卻被你吸引
And me, I was-- I was drawn to you.
我也不知道這是為什麼  但
I couldn't explain why, but...
但是我總覺得我們心靈相通
but a part of me felt connected to you.
你總是會及時地出現
You were always there.
為了我
For me...
為了我的家人
for my family,
而因為某種原因我從來沒問過為什麼
and for some reason, I never asked why.
你現在是在問我嗎
Are you asking now?
不需要了
I don't have to.
因為我已經知道答案了
Because I already know the answer.
喂
Hello?
爸爸出事了
It's dad.
發生什麼了
What is it?
勞蕾爾  我真的很抱歉
Laurel, I am so sorry.
你父親現在處於保護性監禁
We had your father under protective custody.
在鐵山監獄根本就沒有保護性監禁可言
There's no such as thing as protective custody in Iron Heights.
爸爸
Dad!
我沒事的  寶貝  我沒事
It's all right, sweetheart, it's all right.
別 別 別碰我的肋骨
Hey, whoa, don't touch the ribs! The ribs.
我快要厭倦來醫院看我的家人了
I'm getting tired of visiting my family members in a hospital.
發生什麼了
What happened?
只不過是一個老相識過來拜訪我一下
Oh, it's just some old collar paid me a visit.
我想我在監獄裡不太受歡迎
I guess I'm not the most popular guy in prison.
莎拉  你介意我和爸爸單獨聊聊嗎
Sara, do you mind giving Dad and I a second alone, please?
當然不
Yeah, of course.
我就在外面等著
I'll be right outside.
別走太遠  寶貝
Don't go far, sweetie.
爸爸
Dad...
怎麼了  寶貝
What is it, honey?
-我必須要告訴你一件事  -怎麼了
- I have to tell you something. - What is it?
我知道綠箭俠是誰了
I know who the Arrow is.
什麼
What?
不要講出來
Don't say another word.
不要說
Don't say anything.
好吧
Ok.
聽著  我曾經寧願不當員警
Listen to me, there was a time when I would have
也要找出他的真實身份  你知道的
sold out my badge to find out his name. You know that.
但是現在我意識到我已經不在乎了
But then I realize I didn't care who he was.
事實上  我甚至不想知道他是誰了
In fact, I didn't even want to know who he was.
為什麼
Why not?
因為我明白一旦我知道了他是誰
'Cause I knew if I knew who he really was,
他就成為了一個真實的人
then he'd become a person, right?
也許他也有家人和朋友
Maybe he's got a family. Friends.
有在乎他的人
People that care about him.
他也有自己的生活
Someone with a life.
那樣他就不是我需要他成為的樣子了
That he couldn't be what I needed him to be.
不是這個城市需要他成為的樣子了
What this city needs him to be.
綠箭俠這個角色才重要
It's the Arrow that matters.
帽衫下面的人是誰無所謂
The man under the hood isn't important.
你能想像他的生活是什麼樣的嗎
Can you imagine what it's like to be him?
他日復一日的生活
What he has to live with day in and day out,
必須是什麼樣子的
what that's got to be like.
我能做的就是坐在這裡給他一些時間
The least I can do is sit here and do a little bit of time for him.
你父親怎麼樣了
How's your father?
如果你放棄對他的指控
He'll be better once you drop all charges
在釋放文件上簽字那他就更好了
and sign his release papers.
他面臨的可是一年半的監禁
He is facing 18 months.
沒錯  不過他不會再待在監獄裡了
Yes. But he is not going to stay here another day
除非你想讓我辭職
unless you want me to resign
然後開始我的刑事辯護律師生涯
and embark on an exciting new career as a criminal defense attorney
我唯一的志向就是起訴地方檢察官辦公室
whose sole ambition will be to sue the District Attorney's office
非法逮捕和怠忽致危罪
for wrongful arrest and reckless endangerment.
你父親簽了保證書之後
Your father will be released on his own recognizance
一小時之內就會被釋放
within the hour.
明天開始復職
And reinstated. Tomorrow.
給你一個建議
A word of advice--
以後要小心選擇你的對手
be mindful of the battles you choose,
因為不是所有爭鬥都像今天這麼容易
because it will not always be this easy.
法律顧問幹得漂亮
Nice work, counselor.
謝謝
Thank you.
你的胳膊怎麼樣了
How's your arm?
還可以  只有揮手的時候才疼
Fine. Only hurts when I wave.
我沒事的  向你保證
I'm fine, I promise.
我知道你會沒事的
I know you will be.
謝謝
Thanks.
威登酒吧
謝謝你能同意來和我談談
Thank you for agreeing to talk to me.
我只是負責來聽你說的
You're talking. I only agreed to listen.
我只是想說
I just want to start with--
我知道你認為
I know you think that--
等等
Hold on.
費利西蒂  我現在沒時間接電話
I can't talk right now, Felicity.
我明白  但是柯林斯梅因電網數據突增
I know. But the grid at Collins and Main just spiked,
顯示為用電量巨大
drawing a hell of a lot of power,
這意味著要麼有人正在使用
which means someone either
這個世界上最大的吹風機
plugged in the world's largest hair dryer,
要不就是生物疏導器已經開始運行
or the biotransfuser just went online.
這臺機器有特定的動力循環週期
The power cycle on this machine is very specific.
你有三十分鐘時間  最多四十分鐘
You have 30 minutes, 40 tops.
我知道這很自私  奧利弗
I know this is selfish, Oliver,
不要怪我這麼說
and don't hate me for saying this,
但是  你別去
but...don't go.
如果西婭不在那些檔上簽字
If you don't get Thea to sign those documents,
你們家就會失去所有財產
your family loses all of its assets.
如果我不馬上阻止斯萊德
If I don't stop Slade right now,
會有更多人失去更多財產
a lot of people will lose a lot more.
我要是你的話我可不會碰
I wouldn't touch that if I were you.
在運行中動他會害死他的
Removing him mid-cycle will surely end his life.
-斯萊德  他只是個孩子  -他來這裡
- Slade, he's just a kid! - Who's here
是因為你把他拒之門外了
only because you pushed him away.
他之前敬仰的一直是你
You were the one person he looked up to.
可是  你卻傷害了他的心靈
And for that, you crushed his soul.
我們在布魯德海文的一處避難所找到他的
We found him at a shelter in Bludhaven.
太可憐了  連抵抗都沒有抵抗
Pathetic. Didn't even put up a fight.
我會抵抗的
I will.
告訴我怎麼關掉
Tell me how to shut it down.
如果你能感受到我體內洶湧的能量
If you could feel the power that is surging through me...
你就會知道我不怕一隻小小的箭
You would know that I do not fear an arrow.
我遠比你想像的要強大的多
I am stronger than you can even imagine.
馬上...
And soon...
就會有人跟我一樣了
I will not be alone.
你傷害不了我  小子
You can't hurt me, kid.
羅伊  來  堅持住
Come on, Roy. All right, stay with me.
他失血過多
He's lost a lot of blood.
我不知道生物輸液對他造成了什麼影響
I don't know what the biotransfuser did to him.
但是他的脈搏很虛弱  幾乎沒有呼吸了
But his pulse is really weak; He's barely breathing.
他需要真正的醫生
And he needs a real doctor.
不能帶他去醫院  醫院會做各種檢查
We can't take him to a hospital-- they run tests.
不能讓別人知道他體內有什麼東西
We need to keep what's in him from getting out.
那我們該怎麼辦
What do we do now?
我們就只能等著
The only thing we can do-- we wait.
與此同時  斯萊德的問題還沒有解決
Well, while we're waiting, we still have a Slade problem.
他還有20個跟他一樣的人
He's got 20 guys just like him,
我們沒辦法阻止他
and we have no way to stop him.
不  我們有辦法
Yes, we do.
那是我想的東西嗎
Is that what I think it is?
米拉庫魯
Mirakuru.
你不會是想服下這個吧
You weren't thinking about taking it, were you?
不是
No.
我們要用它製造解藥
We're going to use it to make a cure.
奧利弗  我們都不知道
Oliver, we don't even know
它的作用是不是可逆的
if it's possible to reverse the affects.
我們知道
Yes, we do.
艾沃成功過
Ivo did it.
你怎麼不早說  奧利弗
Why didn't you ever tell us that, Oliver?
因為我感覺很慚愧
Because I'm ashamed.
為什麼
Of what?
五年前  我有機會給斯萊德用解藥的
Five years ago, I had the chance to use the cure on Slade.
可我卻選擇了殺他
I chose to kill him.
現在的一切都是我的錯
Everything that's happening right now is my fault.
我救過你一次  莎拉
I saved you once, Sara.
感覺像很久以前的事了
It feels like a long time ago now.
你是時候回報我了
Time to return the favor.
可能你們不會相信
You might not believe it now,
但我以前是個好人
but I was considered a good man.
是個好醫生  好丈夫
A good doctor. A good husband.
可後來米拉庫魯把我變瘋了
Until the Mirakuru drove me mad.
我甚至沒有讓自己...
I didn't even take any myself--
你沒必要為我這麼做的
You didn't have to do that for me.
一旦你殺了人
Once you take a life...
它會永遠改變你的
it changes you forever.
我不想讓你那樣
And I don't want that for you.
謝謝
Thank you.
幸運兒
Schastlivchik.
我們現在怎麼辦
So, now what do we do?
你們應該不會有人知道怎麼開潛艇吧
Well, I don't suppose any of you know how to pilot a submarine?
西婭
Thea.
你幹什麼呢
What are you doing?
收拾東西而已  我覺得
Just grabbing some stuff. Something tells me
這裡的新主人不想讓我的衣服出現在這裡
the mansion's new owner won't want my clothes here.
西婭  等等
Thea, wait.
現在你不忙了啊
Now he's not busy.
對不起  我也無能為力
I'm so sorry, that couldn't be helped.
現在我能跟你說幾句話嗎
May I speak to you now?
爸爸知道真相
Dad knew the truth.
什麼
What?
他知道梅林的事
He knew about Merlyn.
怎麼可能
How?
他從沒跟我提過
He never said anything to me.
沒這個必要
He didn't have to.
西婭  不論爸爸有什麼錯
Thea, whatever dad's faults were...
他都是愛我們的
He loved us.
愛我們所有人
All of us.
因為我們是他的家人
Because we were his family.
你是他女兒
You were his daughter,
一次破驗血不會改變這點
and some stupid blood test wasn't going to change that.
他選擇了我們
He chose us.
他選擇了你
He chose you.
他決定
He made a decision
做你的父親
to be your father,
即使他並不是非這樣不可
even though he didn't have to be.
所以你有什麼感想呢
So what does that tell you?
感想就是他是個騙子
It tells me that he's a liar.
就跟你們倆一樣
Just like both of you.
星城實驗室
我需要你們幫我個忙
I need you guys to do me a favor.
記得保密
This time, it'll be our secret.
威登酒吧
奧利弗
Oliver.
這是幹什麼
What's this for?
因為你對我而言很重要
Because you're important to me.